Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut (1910-2003) 1738-2006 AR 25309 / MF 932
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series II: Elizabeth Strauss Plaut Genealogy, 1847-1999; 3.125 linear feet.
  - Subseries 2: Dreifus/ Dreyfus/ Dreyfoos, 1847-1997; 0.5 linear foot.
    - Arkansas Pappenheimers - Correspondence, 1977-1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Marks, Morton 1989
      Mendelsohn, E.A. 1978
      Moshow, Louise 1977
      Moskow, Lester 1989
      Sanders, Ira E. 1977
      Stein, Bernard 1989
      Stein, Jennings and Bernard 1988-1989
    - Arkansas Pappenheimers - Notes and Clippings, 1892-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Brandeis-Bardin Weekend Institute, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cahn/ Dreyfoos Branch - Correspondence, 1973-1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Cincinnati Censuses, 1847-1862, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cincinnati Directories - Notes, 1974-1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Cincinnati Pappenheimers, 1871, 1987-1992 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1979, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Burglass, Mary 1997
      Dreyfus, A. Stanley 1973-1979
    - Correspondence, 1982-1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Dreyfoos, Alex W. 1982-1987
      Keller, Walter 1982, 1998
    - Correspondence - Auerbach, Sue - Descendants of Helen Guggenheim Dreifus, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - Dreifus Family, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Dreifus, Philip 1973
      Dreyfous, Mathilde 1973
      Keilson, Dan 1973-1974
      Mathieu, Rosella 1973
    - Correspondence - Zelcer, Fannie (American Jewish Archives), 1973-1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Dreifus and Guggenheim Family Members - Switzerland - Notes, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Dreifus/ Wormser Research (Daniel Wormser/ Samuel Dreifus), 1936-1954, 1981-1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Dreifuss, Michel - Branch - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Cohen, Jeska 1981
      Cohen, Therese 1981
    - Dreyfoos, Albert - Branch - Correspondence - Rosen, Joyce, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Dreyfoos, Alexander - Articles and Notes, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Dreyfoos, Alexander - Articles and Notes - Whittemore Family Members, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Dreyfoos, Alexander Wallace, 1876-1982 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Dreyfoos, Dale, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Dreyfoos Family - Cemetery Records - Notes, 1972-1976 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Dreyfoos Family - Cincinnati and New York City Directories - Notes, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Dreyfoos Family - Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Dreyfoos, Dale 1973-1977
      Dreyfoos Family 1973-1979
      Dreyfoos, Jeanne 1975-1979
      Dreyfoos, Wallace 1973-1978
    - Dreyfoos Family - Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      Dreyfoos, Dale 1980-1982
      Dreyfoos Family 1980-1987
      Dreyfoos, Jeanne 1980-1986
      Dreyfoos, Wallace 1980-1988
    - Dreyfoos Family - Correspondence and Notes, 1956-1978 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Dreyfoos Family - Correspondence and Photographs, 1985-1999 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Dreyfoos Family - Naturalization and Immigration - Notes, 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Dreyfoos, Therese Pappenheimer, 1860-1863, 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Dreyfoos, Wallace ("Wally") and Jeanne - Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Dreyfous Family Wheel, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Dreyfus, Charley - Research, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Dreyfus, Getsch - Branch - Family Trees, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Dreyfuss/ Guggenheim Branch (Samuel Wolf Dreyfuss/ Helena (Helen) Guggenheim) - Correspondence and Family Trees, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Dreyfuss/ Guggenheim Branch (Samuel Wolf Dreyfuss/ Helena (Helen) Guggenheim) - Family Trees, 1970s? (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Family Tree - Emmanuel Dreyfus and Sara Guggenheim, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Family Trees - Dreifus/ Dreyfoos/ Pappenheimer, 1970s? (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Family Trees - Wormser/ Pappenheimer/ Dreyfoos, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Goldstein, Adele - The Chatterbox, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Guggenheim, Florence - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Hiller, Richard - Correspondence and Notes, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Hiller, Richard and Betty - Correspondence, 1973-1991 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Hiller, Richard and Betty - Correspondence and Articles, 1961-1992 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Jewish Historical Society of Maryland - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Longini, Albert, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Longini, Albert - Swiss Jews - Maajan Magazine Article, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Moss, Eliza Davis Johnson, undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Myers, Ethel Lieberman - Correspondence and Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Myers, Frank - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Pappenheimer and Dreyfoos Family - Dun and Breadstreet Research, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Pappenheimer Correspondence, 1973-1990 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Pappenheimer, Oscar, 1973-1982 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Rossman, Laura - Notes, 1959, 1970s? (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Sloss/ Gerstle Branch - Franklin, Karen - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Woog Family - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Subseries 3: Kline, 1978-1994; 0.125 linear foot.
    Subseries 3 holds a small amount of papers on the Kline branch of the family, [who were related to the Dreyfoos and Abraham families?]. The majority of papers in this subseries are clippings about the actor Kevin Kline.
    Correspondence in this subseries concerns a photograph of Elizabeth Plaut's brother and Robert Kline in front of a passenger train called the Dixie Flyer. Much of the Kline Family Correspondence is between Elizabeth Plaut and Robert Joseph ("Bobby") Kline and provides genealogical information on the connection between the families.
    A childhood photograph possibly of Kevin Kline, not originally located among the papers of this subseries, can be found in Series VI.
    - Dixie Flyer Photograph - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Kline, Alexander, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Kline Family Correspondence, 1981-1991 (Box 10, Folder 59)
      Kline, Robert Joseph ("Bobby") 1981-1991
      Nathan, Emil 1987
    - Kline, Kevin - Clippings, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Kline, Kevin - Clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Kline, Kevin - Clippings, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Kline, Kevin - Clippings, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Kline, Kevin - Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Kline, Kevin - Clippings, 1984-1994 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Nathan, Peter - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Subseries 4: Rauh/ Mack, 1956-1993; 0.125 linear foot.
    This subseries holds papers relating to the Rauh (spelled alternatively Rau or Raugh) and Mack branches of the family. It is comprised primarily of family trees and correspondence, as well as a significant amount of photocopies of family members' photographs.Correspondence between Elizabeth Plaut and Edgar Mack describes the connection between the Rauh and Mack families, as well as their connection to the Pappenheimer and Newbergh families.
    - Mack, Edgar, 1956, 1981-1990 (Box 10, Folder 67)
      Mack, Edgar 1981-1990
      Frank, Martha 1956
    - Mack, Ted - Rosenbaum Data, undated, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Rau, Moses, undated (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - Rauh and Mack Family Trees, 1980s? (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Rauh (Rau/ Raugh) Family Research, 1976-1981 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - Rauh, Frederick (Fritz) - Correspondence and Family Trees, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - Rauh, Richard - Family Photographs and Trees, undated, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Subseries 5: Wertheimer, 1860-1865, 1975-1993; 0.125 linear foot.
    Subseries 5 contains papers on the Wertheimer and related branches of the family, such as the Gatz, Rauh, and Rie family branches. It is composed primarily of genealogical and personal correspondence, as well as some family trees and photocopies of newspaper articles on individual family members. Extensive genealogical information will especially be found in the correspondence of Philippe Rie, who was also compiling material on the family history.
    - Gatz, Arthur and Marjie - Correspondence, 1977-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Gatz/ Goetz Family - Research, 1860-1865, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Wertheimer, Bella (Wormser) - Data and Records, 1976-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Wertheimer Family - Correspondence, 1975-1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Rauh, Edwin S. (Ted) 1975-1977
      Steinhart, John H. 1993
      Wertheimer, Edgar E. 1989
    - Wertheimer Family - Markus, Edith Sampliner - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Wertheimer Family Tree - Monique Lévi-Strauss, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Wertheimer Family Tree - Rie, Philippe - Correspondence, 1977-1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Wertheimer Family Tree - Rie, Philippe - Wormser Data, 1983? (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: Wisebart, 1873-1995; 0.125 linear foot.
    Subseries 6 is comprised of files relating to the Wisebart branch of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's family. The correspondence in this subseries is personal in nature, with genealogical matters interspersed among the letters exchanged between Elizabeth Plaut and her relatives. Photocopies of articles on nineteenth-century family members will also be found here. Especially prominent in this subseries is material on Frances Wisebart Jacobs of Colorado, who was included in the National Women's Hall of Fame for her charitable activities.Correspondence with Emmett Louis includes family trees displaying the connection between the Dreyfoos and Wisebart families.
    - Jacobs, Frances Wisebart - Research, 1976-1995 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - McGonagle, Clara Jarecki - Correspondence, 1977-1990 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Wisebart, Benjamin, undated, 1895 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Wisebart Data - Correspondence - McGonagle, Clara Jarecki, 1977-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Wisebart Data - Correspondence - Other Individuals, 1977-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Wisebart Data - Notes and Clippings, 1873-1977 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Wisebart Family - Correspondence, 1977-1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Louis, Emmett W. 1977-1991
      Morris, Milton and Jean 1977-1988
    - Wisebart Family Tree - Sampliner Family - Correspondence and Research, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Wresz, Shirley - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 7: Wormser/ Guggenheim, 1850-1996; 1.25 linear feet.
    Separated into the following areas:
    A) S & W (Sussman, Wormser & Co.) Fine Foods
    B) General Wormser Family
    Subseries 7 holds files pertaining to the Wormser family, known originally in Germany as the Guggenheim family before the family moved to the town of Aldingen. Papers in Subseries 7 consist of extensive correspondence, numerous family trees, photocopies of articles and historical documents accumulated during Elizabeth Plaut's research on the family, and genealogical notes.
    Some of the material in this subseries focuses on the branch of the Wormser family which went to the western United States, settling in such places as San Francisco and Deming, New Mexico. Such files include copies of articles and photographs of these locations. Other papers provide information on Lewis Harris (originally Samuel Wormser), who came to Ireland from Germany and almost became Lord Mayor of Dublin.
    Among these papers are several folders that pertain to the history of the S & W Fine Foods company in California, originally begun through a partnership between Samuel Sussman, S.I. Wormser, and Gustav Wormser. Files relating to this branch of the family include some information on the history of the company as well as genealogical material. Included among such papers are family trees and copies of articles on family members descended from this branch of the family and the family residence.
    Several memoirs are present in this subseries that provide a view of family member's lives. Among such accounts is a detailed description by Laurence Klauber of the 1906 San Francisco earthquake and subsequent fire. The memoir of Marion Israella Blitz describes her childhood and early years in Detroit during the late 1800s. Richard Sommer's recollections mention family members he knew as well as his experiences in Nazi Germany.
    - A) S & W (Sussmann, Wormser & Co.) Fine Foods, San Francisco
      - Arnstein, Peter, 1986-1995 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Blumlein Family - Blumlein, Jean - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Blumlein Family - Bush, Nancy E. - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Blumlein Family - Correspondence and Family Trees, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Blumlein Family - Franklin, John - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Company History, 1905-1957, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Company History - Correspondence and Research, 1937-1994 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Company and Family History - Steinberg, Walter R. - Correspondence and Clippings, 1944-1994 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Family History - Notes and Excerpts - Germany, 1866-1894 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Family History - Notes and Excerpts - San Francisco, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Sussman and Guggenheim - Family Trees and Data, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Sussmann Family - Fried, Laurence - Correspondence and Research, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Wormser, Isaac - House, 1971, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - B) General Wormser Family
      - Apt Family, 1986-1992 (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Blumlein Branch - Sloss, Louis, undated, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Cincinnati Cemetery Records - Notes, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Coblentz, Dorothy Wormser - Research, 1987-1993 (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Einstein Branch - Weil, Stephen - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Eaton/ Einstein Branch, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Family Trees - Corrections, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Family Trees - Wormser and Pappenheimer - with Sources, 1976-1980s? (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Frank Family Members, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Frank, Hyman - Memoir of Marion Israella Blitz, undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - Guckenheimer Family Correspondence - Harrison, Elizabeth, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Guggenheim Family from Worms, undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
      - Guggenheim Family - Switzerland, 1978-1998 (Box 11, Folder 43)
      - Guggenheim/ Wormser Family (Book) - Orders, 1995-1998 (Box 11, Folder 44)
      - Guggenheim/ Wormser Family (Book) - Proofs - Index, 1990s? (Box 11, Folder 45)
      - Guggenheim/ Wormser Family (Book) - Publishing - Notes, 1990s? (Box 11, Folder 46)
      - Guggenheimer - Family Trees and Correspondence, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 47)
      - Guggenheimer/ Wertheimer/ Wormser - Notes, 1980s? (Box 11, Folder 48)
      - Guggenheims and Plauts - Friedlaender, Charles J. - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 49)
      - Hirsch, Doelzele Wormser - Branch, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 50)
      - Hirsch, Hans - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 51)
      - Hirsch, Robert - Memoirs, undated, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 52)
      - Hochberg Cemetery, undated (Box 11, Folder 53)
      - Kahn, Ann Elefante - Correspondence, 1972? (Box 11, Folder 54)
      - Klauber, Laurence - Two Days in San Francisco (San Francisco Earthquake), 1906 (Box 11, Folder 55)
      - Klee Family, undated, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 56)
      - Lindauer, Sigmund - Research (Deming, New Mexico), 1930-1957, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 57)
      - Oppenheimer, Adele (Guckenheimer) - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 58)
      - Pappenheimer Branch - Wormser, Laurence - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 59)
      - Pappenheimer, Otto - Branch - Falk, Leonard - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 60)
      - Pappenheimer, Otto - Branch - Research and Correspondence, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 61)
      - Pittsburgh Data - Notes, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 62)
      - Portsmouth (England) Jewish Community - Archives, 1936, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 63)
      - Rie, Philip Paul - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 64)
      - San Francisco Directories, 1980s? (Box 11, Folder 65)
      - San Francisco - Notes, 1980s? (Box 11, Folder 66)
      - Schloss Family Data - Guckenheimer, Ludwig - Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Shavit, Eva (Wormser), 1975-1992 (Box 11, Folder 68)
      - Shavit, Eva (Wormser) - Explanation of the Wormser-Brettauer Family Tree, undated (Box 11, Folder 69)
      - Sommer Family, 1962-1991 (Box 11, Folder 70)
      - Sommer, Richard - Recollections (Memoir), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 71)
      - Uhlmann and Hirsch Families - Correspondence and Notes, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 72)
      - Unsorted Correspondence - Various, 1981-1988 (Box 11, Folder 73)
      - Wertheimer Family - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 11, Folder 74)
      - Wormser, Abraham - Branch - Baer, Uri - Correspondence, 1973-1988 (Box 11, Folder 75)
      - Wormser, Abraham - Branch - Correspondence, 1975-1983 (Box 11, Folder 76)
        Hirsch, Fanny 1975-1983
        Sommer, Paula 1975-1980
        Wormser, Otto 1976
      - Wormser, Abraham - Branch - Correspondence, 1975-1992 (Box 11, Folder 77)
        Baum, Helga D. 1975-1987
        Sommer, Alfred 1981-1982
      - Wormser, Abraham - Branch - Correspondence and Notes, 1975-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Wormser, Abraham - Branch - Correspondence and Notes - Sommer, Alfred H., 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Wormser, Abraham - Data - Correspondence and Research, 1916-1966, 1975-1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Wormser, Arthur - Branch, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Wormser Family - Aldingen, 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Wormser Family - California - Correspondence, 1975-1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        Kauffman, Jane 1986-1992
        Steinhart, John 1975-1986
      - Wormser Family - California - Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        Coblentz, Dorothy ("Dory") 1983-1985
        Lefkowitz, Rosalie 1989-1991
        Mallory, Elizabeth 1984-1991
      - Wormser Family - California - Correspondence - Coblentz, Dorothy ("Dory"), 1975-1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Wormser Family - Correspondence, 1973-1983 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        Asher, Joseph 1975
        Franklin, Karen 1983
        Genealogical Office, Dublin Castle 1973
        Grome, Eugene 1973-1974
        Jacob, Walter 1974
        Lord Mayor's Office, Dublin, Ireland 1973
      - Wormser Family - Frank, Isaac W., 1984 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Wormser Family - Frank, James - Correspondence, 1973-1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Wormser Family - William Frank Data - Correspondence, 1973-1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
        Half, Madeline 1988
        Jacob, Walter 1973
        Levin, Louise 1988
        Mallinger, Stephanie Frank 1979-1980
        Sussman, Dale 1976
      - Wormser Family - Philadelphia Inquiries, 1980-1986 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Wormser Family Data - General, undated, 1973-1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Wormser Family Tree - Progeny of Samuel Wormser, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Wormser Family Trees, 1980s? (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Wormser/ Guggenheimer - Correspondence and Research, 1988-1999 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Wormser, Gustav - Correspondence - Excerpts and Translations, 1881-1896, 1980s? (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Wormser, Isaac- Branch - Records and Research - Frank Family, 1874-1910, 1965-1992 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Wormser, Jette - Prayerbook Pages and Cover, undated, 1852-1869 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Wormser, Laurence - Correspondence and Notes, 1920, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Wormser, Michael - Branch (Phoenix), 1954, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Wormser, Samuel (Lewis Harris) - Branch - Hyman, Louis - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Wormser, Samuel (Lewis Harris) - Branch - Notes, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Wormser, Samuel (Lewis Harris) - Notes - Jews in Ireland, 1970s-1980s? (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - Wormser, Samuel (Lewis Harris) - Research (Ireland), 1975-1990 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Wormser, Sigmund - Autobiography, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Series III: General and Unsorted Genealogical Files, 1950-1999; 0.75 linear foot.
  Alphabetical
  Series III holds files accumulated during Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's genealogical research. Most of these papers were not identified as belonging to a single branch of the Plaut and Strauss family genealogies. The majority of these files consist of notes taken from various city directories where family members resided. Other files include correspondence with historical institutions. Several folders in this subseries were unidentified, and folder titles were assigned during processing.
  - American Jewish Archives - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Atlanta - Notes and Clippings, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Baltimore - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Berman, Roberta - Notes, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Census Data - Notes - Plaut/ Wormser/ Dreifus, 1976-1978? (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Cincinnati Census Data, 1980s? (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Cincinnati Jewish Community - Article, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Cincinnati - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - City Directories - Notes, 1980s? (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - England - Research Sources, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - English and Irish Research Sources - University of Waterloo Library - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Family Correspondence - Personal, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Florida - Notes, undated, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Genealogical Research Sources - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - German Script - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - German Sources, undated, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Israel - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Jewish Genealogical Society of Canada - Correspondence and Notes, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Jewish Genealogical Society of New York City - Directory of Family and Place Names, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Lancaster County, Pennsylvania - Legal Records, undated (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Loose Papers - Correspondence and Notes, 1950-1997 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Loose Papers - Correspondence and Notes, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Loose Papers - Manuscript Draft Pages, 1990s? (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Loose Papers - Poetry and Songs, undated (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Loose Papers - Programs and Publications - Public Appearances of Plaut Family Members, 1971-1997 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Loose Papers - Thomas China (Canada) Ltd., 1980s? (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - New York City Department of Health, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - New York City Directories and Censuses - Notes, 1978-1982 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Notecards - Loose - Unidentified Family, 1973-1987 (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Notecards - Plaut Family - Chronological, 1976-1991 (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Notecards - Plaut Family - Unsorted, 1979-1988 (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Notecards - Strauss Family, 1973-1999 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Jews - Articles, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reeves, Roma, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - San Diego and San José - Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Scarsdale - Notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Skirball Museum - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified Family - Hebrew Union College Graduation Program, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Unsorted Notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Vilna Gaon Research - Friedman, Chaim, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Wittenberg Article - The Roots of German Anti-Semitism by Giveon Cornfield, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)